You don't need extraordinary powers to do extraordinary things.
The Wild Thornberrys Movie is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Cathy Malkasian.
Eliza and Debbie are two sisters who don't always get along.
But their relationship is put to the test when Debbie's life is in danger, and
Eliza might have to give up her power to talk to animals....
Eliza Thornberry (voice), played by Lacey Chabert.
Darwin (voice), played by Tom Kane.
Phaedra (voice), played by Cree Summer.
Nigel Thornberry (voice), played by Tim Curry.
Cordelia Thornberry (voice), played by Lynn Redgrave.
Debbie Thornberry (voice), played by Danielle Harris.
The Wild Thornberrys Movie is a 2002 American animated adventure comedy film
produced by Klasky Csupo, based on the television series.
It was written by Kate Boutilier, and features the voices of Lacey Chabert, Tom Kane, Danielle
Harris, Jodi Carlisle, Tim Curry, Lynn Redgrave, Rupert Everett, Marisa Tomei, and Flea.
The film follows Eliza Thornberry as she goes on a quest to
save a cheetah cub from ruthless poachers.
It is the first installment in The Wild Thornberrys film series.
The film's music score was written by series composer Drew Neumann.
The Wild Thornberrys Movie was released on December 20, 2002, by
Paramount Pictures through their Nickelodeon Movies label.
It received positive reviews and grossed $61 million worldwide.
The film was nominated for Best Original Song at the 75th Academy
Awards for Paul Simon's "Father and Daughter".
A sequel, and a crossover with characters from Rugrats
titled Rugrats Go Wild, was released in 2003.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
safari, villain, wildlife, baboon.
The tone is lighthearted.